I order you as the Deputy King of Balbadd!
（サブマド）バルバッド副王の名において
命じる！
第三王子アリババと
現王との会談を妨げること→
The conversation between 3rd Prince
Alibaba and the King is not to be interrupted!
断じてならん！
So you want a coup d'etat?
（アブマド）
クーデターということだな!?
Ahbmad!
（アリババ）アブマド！
俺は　お前と　この国の現状に→
I have come to put an end to the status quo in this country!
引導を渡しに来た！
♪♪～
≪（紅玉）ねえ　夏黄文→
Hey Ka Koubun.
なんだか
王宮の中が　騒がしくな～い？
Do you hear something coming from the palace?
（夏黄文）結納品の検品でも
されているのでしょう。→
They may be inspecting your betrothal gifts.
Or perhaps preparing for the signing and marriage ceremonies that are taking place tomorrow.
もしくは
明日の調印と　婚礼の儀の準備…。
ん？
あっ。
♪♪～
miwatasu kagiri no kouya ni hitori tatteirunda
In the wilderness, as far as the eye can see, stands a lone figure
sorya miburui mo surun darou
Surely he trembles as he stands
♪♪～
osanai shoujo ga yume ni miteiru hakuba no ouji mitaina mono
A young girl dreams of a prince on a white horse
♪♪～
bokura mo dokka de shiranai uchi ni kitai shiteshimatteitano kamo
Unwittingly, we also fall to such dreams of perfection
fukanzen na kono sekai wo dareka ga
No one will recreate
♪♪～
kakitashite kureru nante nai
this imperfect world for us
♪♪～
shinjiru toiu kotoba wo kimi ha kodomoppoi to warau kai?
Will you call me naïve if I say that I still dream?
miwatasu kagiri no kouya de yukisaki wo shimesu mono
In the wilderness, as far as the eye can see, shines a guiding light
♪♪～
mune ni daite aruitekou sekai ga hohoemu
Hold it close as you go and the world will smile upon you
kono basho ga doko darou to miagereba mabataku hoshi
If you're lost, consult the twinkling stars
♪♪～
sono shita de kimi wo omoeba warukunai yoru ni naru
If I think of you while gazing at those stars, the night brightens
tsumetai mune ni hi ga tomoru
and a warm fire lights in my heart
14th Night
Alibaba's Answer
ドカッドカッ！　ドカッ！（蹴る音）
キィー！
ドカッ！
ギィー！
ギギィ…
キィー　キィ…
キィ…
キッ　キッ…
（モルジアナ・心の声）≪私の力で
できるのは　ここまでです≫
This is all I can do.
I hope you are able to do what you set out to do, Alibaba.
≪どうか　あなたのやりたいことを
果たしてください　アリババさん≫
♪♪～
Sahbmad, it was you who leaked
information to those thieves, wasn't it?
サブマド　本当に　賊と→
通じておったというのだな？
Yes.
そうだ。
はっ！　気でも狂ったか!?
Have you lost your mind?
You're the crazy one, Ahbmad.
（サブマド）
おかしいのは　兄さんの方だ。
明日の調印式では→
You plan on signing the people of Balbadd into slavery at the ceremony tomorrow.
国民総奴隷化なんて条約まで
結ぼうとしている。
（一同）えっ？
お前　まさか　余に代わって
王になろうという魂胆か？
You want to become king in my place, don't you? That's your ulterior motive, isn't it?
ち…　違う。　僕には
そんなつもりも　資格もない。
No. I do not have plans or the capability to become king.
No plans? Not capable?
つもり？　資格？
You caused a coup d'etat as Deputy King. How are you going to take responsibility for it?
こんなクーデターを起こした副王に→
その責任がないとでも言うのか!?
（サブマド）うわっ…。
ここに立て！
Try standing here!
ここから　王族の責任が
どんなものか　見渡してみろ！
What does it feel like to carry the responsibilities of a king?
あっ！
♪♪～
They aren't the only ones you need to answer to.
こいつらだけじゃないぞ。→
余を　王位から引きずり降ろせば→
If you take the crown from me, you will have to answer to the expectations of all the people of Balbadd.
外にいる国民たちすべてが
お前に期待する。
And they will hang onto your every word.
そして　お前の言葉
一言一句に　耳を澄ませる。
（サブマド）ああっ…　あぁ…。
うぅ…　ああっ…。→
うっ…。
ははっ！　そうだ→
That's right!
お前は
他人が怖くて　何も言えない…→
You can't do it! You're a coward who's afraid of
speaking in front of others! You can't do anything!
何もできない臆病者ではないか！
≫やめろよ！
あっ？
Stop that!
Sahbmad isn't a coward.
サブマド兄さんは　臆病じゃねぇ。
身の危険を冒して
霧の団のアジトに→
He risked his life to come to the Fog
Troupe's hideout and speak with me.
話をしに来てくれた。
And he just took control of this situation and saved my life!
さっきだって
この場を収め　俺を助けてくれた。
アリババ…。
だから　サブマド兄さんは→
Alibaba...
Sahbmad is definitely not a coward.
絶対に　臆病者なんかじゃない。
勇気のある人なんだ！
うぅ…　ううっ…。
He's a brave hero!
（アブマド）ふ…　ふ…→
Shut up, both of you worthless fools!
ふざけるな！　このゴミどもが～!!
くっ！　ふん！
（アブマド）うわっ…。　あっ！
バシ！
（アブマド）がっ！
ううっ！
アブマド→
Ahbmad.
お前の在位中は
煌帝国の執拗な介入で→
It's true that during your reign, the
persistent intervention of the Kou Empire
正しい政治を行うのが
困難だったのは確かだ。
prevented you from implementing good policies.
But we can no longer accept a king who allows our country to be driven into a dead-end like this!
しかし
国を　ここまで追い詰めた者が→
これ以上の　かじを取るのは
誰も納得しない。
だから　今　この場をもって
王位を退いてもらう！
So use this chance to resign from the throne immediately!
余…　余が王ぞ…。　殺せ～！
I-I'm the king...  Kill him!
国王暗殺を企てた反逆者だ！
He's a traitor who's trying to kill the king!
捕らえて　即刻　打ち首にせよ！
Capture him and behead him at once!
余が…　余が…
バルバッド国２３代国王→
I... I am the 23rd King of Balbadd,
アブ…　アブ…　アブマド…→
Ahb...  Ahb...  Ahbmad Saluja...
アブマド・サルージャ…。
もう　とっくに終わってるんだよ→
You were finished a long time ago, Brother.
兄さん。
I am...  I am...
余が…　余が…　余が！
あぁ…　ううっ…。
≪（紅玉）一体　なんの騒ぎなの？
What is with all the commotion?
あっ…　どうしよう？　アリババ。
Oh no! What should we do now, Alibaba?
たぶん
あの人が　兄さんの婚約者…。
She's probably Ahbmad's fiancée.
Now.
≪来た。　ここからが→
Now is the moment to set things right!
俺の本当にやるべきことを
果たすとき≫
（Ｓナンド）はぁ　はぁ！
急げ！　この国は　もう終わりだ。
Hurry! This country's done for!
大ごとに
巻き込まれる前に　逃げるんだ。
We're getting out of here before we get caught in the crossfire!
（Ｌナンド）でも　いいのかな？　これは
シンドバッドさんのもので…。→
Can we really take these? They're Sinbad's...
What if they're metal vessels?
もし　これが　金属器だったら→
とっても必要なものなんじゃ…。
う～ん…。
He'll need them!
（Ｓナンド）んん…。
（Ｍナンド）兄上　あれを！
（２人）ん？
Brother, look over there!
（Ｍナンド　Ｌナンド）あぁ…。
（Ｓナンド）なんだ？　あれ。
What's that?
あっ！
（ジャーファル）
ルフが　はっきり見えるまでに→
So much rukh has gathered that it has become visible to the human eye!
集まってきている。
♪♪～
（銀行屋）何やら　あちこちで→
Oh my. So much is coming to fruition.
いろんなことが
起きているようですねぇ。
♪♪～
（武器商人）
これも　すべて歴史の局面。→
All is as history wrote.
運命は　やがて
巨大なうねりとなり　堕転する。
Fate is but a swinging pendulum, easily swung into depravity.
（紅玉）
騒ぎを聞きつけて　参りました。→
I heard the commotion and came to see what was the matter.
私は　煌帝国第八皇女　練紅玉。
I am the 8th Imperial Princess of the Kou Empire, Kougyoku Ren.
アブマド王の婚約者です。
I am King Ahbmad's betrothed.
（一同）ああっ…。
I apologize, but I do not yet know the face of the king.
失礼。　私　まだ
国王様のお顔を　存じ上げないの。
どなたが　国王様なのかしら？
Who here is the king of Balbadd?
余…　余である！
I-I am!
うっ…。
I see.
そう。
（銀行屋）それがですねぇ　姫君→
About that, Princess.
We don't know who the king is at the moment.
どなたが王様なのか
分からないんですよ。
（アブマド）ぬっ!?
We just experienced a coup d'etat and
Ahbmad is going to abdicate the throne.
たった今
クーデターが起きまして→
どうやら　アブマド様は
退位なされるようで。
D-Damn you, Banker!
ぎ…　銀行屋　貴様～！
（紅玉）≪退位？　私は→
He's going to abdicate? Which means I don't need to marry him?
あの方とは　結婚しなくても
いいということ？≫
≪ダメだわ…　落ち着いて≫
No wait, I must remain calm.
≪とにかく　与えられた使命を
果たさなくては≫
I need to carry out the mission entrusted to me.
I have come to marry the king of Balbadd and sign the treaty our countries agreed upon.
私は　バルバッド国王と婚姻し→
条約を　結びに来たのです。→
どなたになろうと
変わりありません。
My purpose will not change no matter who the king is.
Please select a new king now.
新しい国王様を
お決めになってください。
（バルカーク）順当にいけば
あなたが　次の国王です→
Following proper succession order, you would be next, Deputy King.
副王様。
僕に　その資格はないよ。
I am not qualified to be king.
兄さんの悪政を
今日まで　止めもせずに→
I did not stop my brother's misrule of the country until today.
見ていた。　兄さんと同罪だ。
I watched him do it. I am just as guilty.
But there is someone else who has wanted to save this country just as much as I have.
でも　このバルバッドを
何度も救おうとした人が→
僕のほかにいる。
あっ。
♪♪～
あなたが　新しい国王になるの？
Will you become the new king?
俺は　国王にはなりません。
I will not.
あっ！
ええっ!?
（バルカーク）なっ！
あぁ…。
王になる資格なんかないよ。
I'm not qualified to be king either.
俺は　先王を死に追いやる
きっかけを招き→
I enabled the incident that led to the previous king's death, then abandoned this country.
国を捨てて逃げた
無責任な人間だ。
I have been extremely irresponsible.
（紅玉）あなたは？
Who are you?
I am the third prince, Alibaba Saluja.
第三王子　アリババ・サルージャ。
あなたを
煌帝国の代表と見込んで→
I have a request to ask of you, the representative of the Kou Empire.
お願いがあります。
何かしら？
And what might that be?
明日　結ばれる
バルバッド国民の→
I would like you to annul the Treaty of the Transfer of Human Rights that was to be signed tomorrow.
人権委譲条約を
破棄していただきたい。
That treaty was agreed upon with the former king.
あれは　前王が決めたこと。
ほかの者は皆
国民の人権委譲条約など→
No one else wishes for such a treaty to be signed into law.
望んでいません。
（紅玉）そのようね。
だけど　条約は　破棄できないわ。→
It appears that way.
But I cannot annul the treaty.
これは
国同士の取り決めだから。→
It was decided upon by both of our countries.
私は　明日　新しい国王と結婚し…。
Tomorrow, I will marry the new king-
それは　できません。
共に　調印式を行い…。
You will not be able to.
-and, at the same time, carry out the signing ceremony-
それも　できません。
あなた　何を言ってるの!?
You cannot do that either.
What are you saying?
なぜなら　次の国王には
誰も　ならないからです。
You can't do either of those things because there will be no next king of Balbadd.
What do you mean?
どういうこと？
バルバッド王国は→
The kingdom of Balbadd is to immediately cease monarchic rule.
今日で　王政に　終止符を打ちます。
はっ！
（２人）なっ！
アリババ王子は　どうなったんだ？
国を変えるって言ってたけど…。
How is Prince Alibaba doing?
He said he was going to change this country, but how?
この国は　どうなるんだろう？
分からない…。
What will happen to Balbadd?
I don't know...
けど　私はただ　家族と→
All I want is to live happily with my family without going hungry!
飢えずに　幸せに暮らしたい…。
うわぁ～ん！　ああ～…。
国民が欲しいのは
王ではなく　幸せな暮らしだ。
The people don't want a king.
They want to live happily.
Even without a king, they can do that.
王がいなくても
民は　立派に暮らすことができる。
そういう国々を
俺は　砂漠を旅しながら見てきた。
In my journey across the desert, I have seen
many thriving countries without monarchies.
I believe Balbadd should become one of them.
バルバッドも
そうなるべきだと　俺は思う。
（アブマド）
んん…　貴様　ふざけるな！→
Are you out of your mind?
２３代続いたバルバッド王家を→
Are you trying to destroy 23 generations of Balbadd royalty?
滅ぼすというのか～!?
このままでは→
If we don't, the entire country will be destroyed!
どちらにしろ　この国は滅びる！
（アブマド）あっ…。
If a king brings nothing but suffering to the people, get rid of him.
国民を苦しめるだけの王なら
なくそう。
国民が　自分たちで代表を選び→
The people can choose their own representatives, set up a republic, and hold congress.
市民政府を作り　議会を開く。
The people themselves should be the ones who decide how their country should be.
国のあり方は
国民自身が決めるんだ。
バルバッドを
格差のない共和制市民国家にする。
Let's turn Balbadd into a People's Republic,
with no more disparity between the classes!
それが
今日　俺が提示しに来たことだ！
That is what I came to the palace to say!
（３人）えっ!?
王政廃止…。
Abolish the monarchy...
He wants to abolish the monarchy?
（紅玉）
≪君主をなくすというの!?≫
Then he's right. I really won't be able to get married or sign the treaty tomorrow!
≪それでは
本当に　明日の婚姻も調印も→
どうしていいか
分からなくなるじゃない≫
And, if the people allow, I want to devote my body and soul
そして　もし許されるなら→
俺も　新しい国作りに関わって→
一生　懸けて
バルバッドに　力を尽くしたい！
to recreating the country of Balbadd!
≫（シンドバッド）やれやれ。　それが
君の答えなんだね　アリババ君。
Oh dear.
So that's your answer, Alibaba?
Sinbad!
シンドバッドさん！
はっ！
I apologize for interrupting right in the
middle of such important matters of state.
（シンドバッド）国の大事の最中だろうが
失礼させていただこう。
（兵士）シンドバッド王と…。
（兵士）誰だ？
Who are those people with King Sinbad?
（シンドバッド）
彼らは　俺の指揮する連合のうち→
They are the diplomatic directors of three countries in the alliance that I command.
三か国の外交長官たちさ。
Alliance?
連合？
（バルカーク）七海連合…。→
The Seven Seas Alliance.
シンドバッド王が作った
七か国同盟。
The alliance King Sinbad formed
between seven different countries.
（サブマド）そんな国々の
外交長官たちが　なぜここに？
Why are the diplomatic directors of those countries here?
（シンドバッド）
アルババ・サルージャ王子を→
To recommend Prince Alibaba Saluja to be the king of Balbadd.
バルバッド国王に
推挙するために。→
バルバッドを救うには
君を　王にするのがいいと思って→
I thought that you needed to become king in order to save Balbadd, so I called them over.
彼らを呼んだんだ。→
But you thought of a completely different method.
しかし　君は　まったく違うことを
考えていたようだね。
黙って　勝手をして　すみません。
I apologize for going off by myself and not saying anything.
だけど　これが　俺の答えです。
But this is my answer.
（紅玉）お待ちになって。
生まれ変わるだの　共和制だの→
Please wait!
What do you mean by recreate? And the People's Republic?
何を勝手なことを！　あなた→
Have you forgotten?
お忘れに
なっているのではなくて？→
All of Balbadd's rights have been transferred to the Kou Empire as collateral for Balbadd's many loans.
バルバッドのあらゆる利権は
すべて　借金の担保として→
我が煌帝国に　譲渡されていてよ。
よく分かっています。
I am well aware of that.
This country owns nothing. Even if its organization were to change, those rights will not return.
この国には　何もない。
体制を変えても→
それは　解決しない。
（紅玉）ふっ。
だから
それらの権利を譲渡したことを→
Therefore, I would like you to pretend that those transfers of rights did not happen!
すべて　なかったことに
していただきたい！
（紅玉）はあ？
What?
はっ！
The kingdom of Balbadd that you speak of no longer exists.
あなたのおっしゃる
そのバルバッド王国は→
もはや
滅びて　存在しない国なのです。
The country that is being created now is a completely different, new entity.
これから形成されるのは
まったく新しい別の国。
故に　煌帝国と交わした約束が→
As such, it does not need to inherit the old treaties established with the Kou Empire!
引き継がれようはずもないのです。
そうでしょう!?
Don't you agree?
（紅玉）あっ…。
（夏黄文）≪くだらない屁理屈だ。→
What a ridiculous argument.
国家間で
正式に交わされた条約が→
There is no way that formally signed,
cross-national agreements can be written off so easily.
帳消しとなるわけがない≫
≪強引すぎる屁理屈だ≫
I am forcing my argument.
≪それは　分かっている。
しかし…≫
I know what I'm saying is unreasonable, but...
At any rate, the fact that there is no one for you to marry tomorrow stands.
とにかく　明日の　あなたの
結婚相手がいないことは→
事実でしょう。
すべての条約を破棄する件→
Will you consider bringing my request to annul all former
treaties back to the Kou Emperor first before we proceed?
ひとまず　皇帝陛下のもとへ
持ち帰っていただけますか？
（紅玉）くだらない。
"What nonsense."
Exactly. Just dismiss all of his arguments immediately.
≪そう　そう。
今すぐ　はねのけてしまえば→
よいのであります≫
...is what my father will say when I bring your request back him.
って…　持ち帰ったところで→
お父様は
はねのけるに決まっていてよ。
≪持ち帰ったところでって…→
Bring back to him?
何を言いだすのです　姫君！≫
What are you saying princess?
I guessed right. She's not interested in fighting this very hard.
≪やっぱり…
この人　そんなに押しが強くない≫
≪それに　今回の政略結婚だって
乗り気には見えない≫
In fact, she doesn't seem interested in this political marriage at all.
≪一か八か　そこをつけば≫
That could be my trump card...
Your mission to marry the king of Balbadd cannot be fulfilled.
あなたの目的であった婚姻は
果たせません。
お帰りください。
Please return home.
The Kou Empire's goal was to gain country of this
land completely and without too much bloodshed.
（紅玉）煌帝国の目的は　この地を→
無傷で
手に入れることでしたのよ。→
If he is unable to, he may decide to turn to militaristic methods.
それが果たせぬのなら　父は
軍事行動に出るかもしれませんね。
Please ask him to dispense with that ambition as well!
それも見逃せと　お伝えください。
（紅玉）
あっ…。　なんて　ずうずうしいの！
You... impudent child!
I am not asking him to do so for nothing in return.
もちろん　タダでとは言いません。
無傷で　手に入れたときに
勝るとも劣らぬ利益を→
We will return the favor with the profits that we bring in from our maritime trade.
Those profits will not be less than what the
Kou Empire could gain by taking over now.
我が国との海洋貿易にて→
そちらに　お返しいたします。
バルバッドは
東南随一の海洋貿易の要。
Balbadd is the most powerful cornerstone of southeastern maritime trade.
そこを　戦火で
不毛のさら地にすることと→
Will you set fire to this land through war and turn it into barren ground,
温情を与えて　利潤を得ること→
or will you treat us kindly and reap our profits?
The choice is yours.
どちらを選ばれますか？
軍事力だけではない　政治手腕で→
If the Kou Emperor is truly a wise man, with not only military strength but also political prowess,
煌帝国を栄えさせた
賢明な陛下ならば→
一体　どちらを選ばれるでしょう？
which one do you think he will choose?
（夏黄文）≪ダメだ　姫君！
通らぬと言ってください≫
Don't listen to him, Princess!
Tell him you won't!
（紅玉）通らないわ　そんな理屈。
I won't listen to your flawed logic.
（夏黄文）≪はぁ…≫
≪（シンドバッド）陛下は　軍事行動は
執らないと思いますよ。→
I don't think His Majesty of the Kou
Empire will turn to military conquest.
Because the Republic of Balbadd will join the Seven Seas Alliance.
なぜなら　バルバッド共和国は→
七海連合に入るからです。→
侵略しない　させないが
我ら七海連合の理念。→
We do not invade, nor do we allow
others to invade us. That is our creed.
陛下も　我々には　一目
置いてくださっているはずです。
I believe His Majesty respects our Alliance and our beliefs.
（紅玉）ええ。　でも→
That is true.
But will you really include Balbadd in the powerful  Seven Seas Alliance?
それほどの七海連合に
バルバッドなんかを加えると？
果たして　本当かしら？
I don't know if I can believe that.
It's true!
本当です。
かねてからの約束でした。
It's an agreement that has been in the works for some time now.
我がバルバッド国は
先々代の王の頃より→
Balbadd has had very close relations with Sindria since the time of the king two generations ago.
シンドリアとは　実に親交深い。
（紅玉）そうなの？　夏黄文。
（夏黄文）それは…→
Is that true, Ka Koubun?
That is true, but that has nothing to do with the current situation!
確かですが
それとこれとは関係ありません！
ふぅ…。
この件　陛下に
お任せした方が　よさそうね。
It seems like it would be better to leave this matter to His Majesty.
んっ…　ええ～!?
What?!
I have a condition if I am to withdraw here.
（紅玉）ただし
退くのには　条件があります。
It is on the matter of Balbadd joining the Seven Seas Alliance.
バルバッド　七海連合入りの件→
If it really is the truth, I ask that you come to the Kou Empire and prove it, King Sinbad.
真実ならば　我が皇帝の前に→
証明しに来なさい　シンドバッド王。
必ず　伺おう。
I most certainly will.
Then that is all.
（紅玉）それでは。
P-Please wait, Princess!
（夏黄文）
お…　お待ちください　姫君！
Thank goodness. I don't have the power to make such a decision.
≪よかったわ。　こんな決断は→
私の手に余るもの。　それに…→
And...
あんな豚みたいのと結婚なんて
死ぬほど嫌だった≫
I'd rather die than marry that pig!
（夏黄文）姫君！　姫～!?
Princess!
Princess!!
（一同）おおっ…。
助かったのか？
We're safe?
He faced the Kou Empire without letting up a single step and achieved an acceptable resolution for all parties.
≪あの煌帝国を相手に→
一歩も退かず
この場を収めてしまった≫
やった～！
やったぞ～！
あっ…。
（サブマド）アリババ！　アリババ～！
Alibaba!
（シンドバッド）≪アリババ君→
Alibaba, you just might become someone amazing one day.
君は　もしかして
すごい人物に　なるのかもな≫
♪♪～
（夏黄文）姫君
神官殿は　お連れしなくても→
Princess, are you sure it was all right to leave the Lord Priest?
よいのでありますか？
（紅玉）いいのよ。→
It's fine! Banker said to leave Judal to him!
銀行屋が任せろと言うのだもの。→
早く　お父様に　バルバッド国の→
I must hurry and tell father about how Balbadd has abolished its monarchy!
王政廃止を伝えなくては。→
I'll have to tell him about Sindria's promise as well!
シンドリア国王との約束の件も！
ああっ！
Oh goodness, I wonder when he'll come visit?
≪あの人　いつ
訪ねていらっしゃるのかしら？≫
うふっ！
はぁ…。
You are too rash.
（シンドバッド）
まったく…　君は　むちゃをするよ。
すみません　勝手なことして。
I'm sorry for acting on my own.
（シンドバッド）これから　どうする？
What do you plan to do now?
共和国体制を形作るには
国民から　代表者を募って→
In order to build a republic, we need to gather
representatives from the populous and hold council.
民会を開く必要があります。
まず　そのために
暫定政府を→
In order to do that, I was thinking of establishing a temporary government.
作ろうと思います。
（バルカーク）なるほど。
That makes sense.
（サブマド）兄さんは　どうなるのかな？
What will happen to Ahbmad?
The people will want to see him executed, I'm sure.
（バルカーク）国民は
死刑にせよと言うでしょう。→
だが　それは　我々も同罪。
（サブマド）んん…。
But we also bear the same crimes.
Instead of death, let us work our whole lives as recompense.
（バルカーク）共に
死をもって償うといたしましょう。
Wait! Right now, this country does not have the ability to punish anyone.
待て。　今　この国では
誰かを処罰することはできない。
刑法だって
これから　みんなで考えて→
Because we're going to rewrite our entire penal code as well, right?
作り直すところだからな。
みんなで　力を合わせて
少しずつ　体制を整えていこう。
Let's all work together to slowly build Balbadd back up again.
I believe we should emulate the city-state Kashugan in the Central Desert.
俺は　共和制への移行に
成功して栄えた→
中央砂漠の都市国家
カシュガンの→
They have also switched over to a
republic and are now very successful.
政治形態を踏襲したい。
I believe Balbadd should also, like Kashugan,
バルバッドも　あの国のように→
誰もが　平等に　政治に携われる→
become a pure democracy where all people can equally participate in government.
徹底民主主義を行う国に
生まれ変わるんだ。
本気なんだね　君は。
You're really serious about this.
うん。
I wonder how well that will go.
≪（銀行屋）
そうはうまくいきますかねぇ。
I have seen many different countries,
私は　さまざまな国を
渡り歩きましたが→
共和制国家には
必ず　支配者が生まれ→
and in all republics, a ruler always pushes himself above the people,
and causes the republic to fail.
やがて　瓦解していく。　結局は→
In the end, people need to be ruled.
群衆も　支配を
必要としているのです。
I'm sure that a king will rise up again in this country as well.
この国にも
また　王になろうとする者が→
現れるでしょう　必ずね。
I'd bet on it.
それでも
俺は　格差のない国のあり方を→
Even so, I want to try to create a country without inequality.
模索します。
≫（衛兵）アリババ王子。→
Prince Alibaba.
The people of Balbadd are pressing in on the palace.
外に　民衆が
あふれ返っています。→
そろそろ抑えきれません。
分かった　すぐ行く。
We can no longer hold them back.
I understand. I'll go speak to them now.
（歓声）
Everyone! Please listen to me!
みんな　聞いてくれ！
Today, King Ahbmad has abdicated the throne.
今日の　この日をもって
アブマド国王は退位した。
（歓声）
だが　次の国王はいない。
But there is no king to succeed him.
Instead, Balbadd will cease to be a
monarchy and recreate itself as a republic.
なぜなら
バルバッドは　王政を廃止し→
共和制を取ることにしたからだ。
（どよめき）
The kingdom of Balbadd will recreate itself as the Republic of Balbadd!
バルバッド王国は
バルバッド共和国へと　生まれ変わる！
共和制？
王がいない国になるのか？
Republic?
We're going to become a country without a king?
♪♪～
これも歴史の流れ。　やはり
やむをえないようですねぇ。
This is also a part of history.
It is unescapable.
♪♪～
（武器商人）我々が動けば
向こうも対抗してくるだろうがな。
If we act, I am sure the opposition will not stay quiet.
What is going on?
うわっ！　なんだ!?
（ジャーファル）ルフが…。
The rukh!
♪♪～
共和制とは　自分たちで
自分を治めるということ。
In a republic, the people rule themselves.
In my opinion, that is what the people of Balbadd have already been doing.
だけど　そんなことは
もう　ここにいるみんなが→
やっていることだと　俺は思う。
In this crippled country, inflicted with heavy
taxation, poverty, stress, and many other injustices,
この傾いた国の中で　重税→
貧困　圧力→
さまざまなものと戦いながら
自分と家族という→
you have protected your families as though they were you own territories and governed yourselves to the best of your ability.
小さな領地を守り抜き
治めてきた人たち→
それが　ここにいる
あなたたちではないのか？
Is that not so?
この世界には
まだ　さまざまな戦乱や混乱→
There is still much war and chaos and abnormality in this world.
異変が　あふれてる。
None of us are immune from those things.
それは
これからも　あなたたちの身に→
降りかかってくることだろう。
だけど　その度に
また　どうすればいいか→
But when they befall us, and we find
ourselves searching for a course of action,
みんなで　考えればいい。
all we need to do is band together and think of a solution.
Even when the solution isn't that obvious,
答えを出すのが
難しいときにでも→
we will come up with one that allows us to live happily with our families and with bravery in our hearts!
自分が　家族と
幸せに暮らす方法を考えて→
選び取る。　勇気を持って！
Let us carve a path with our own two hands and create a place where we can live in happiness!
全員の足で　踏み締めて
この地で生きていこう。
That place is the new country of Balbadd!
それが　新しいバルバッドの姿だ！
The Republic of Balbadd!
バルバッド共和国…。
バルバッド～！
バルバッド！
アリババ様！
アリババ様～！
♪♪～
≪もう俺は　ここから逃げないよ≫
I will no longer run from here.
≪お前との約束　ちょっと→
I'm going to have to put off our promise for a little bit though.
先延ばしになっちまうけどさ≫
（アラジン・回想）
((一緒に冒険しようね))
Let's go on an adventure together!
Wait for me, Aladdin.
≪待っててくれよ　アラジン≫
≪しっかり
やり遂げてみせるからさ≫
I'm going to do this right!
（ジャーファル）アラジン…。→
Aladdin?
えっ？　アラジン　まさか…。
Aladdin! He couldn't have-!
It's here.
（武器商人）来たか。　さあ　運命よ→
Swing, pendulum.
大いに　逆流するがいい。
Reverse the flow of fate!
♪♪～
"kimi ni ha yuuki ga aru"
"You're a hero."
sono hitokoto wo shinji tobidashita
Off you went, believing in those words
mawari ha kare wo waratte
Those around you mock you
♪♪～
"douse nani hitotsu aitsu ni ha dekinai sa"
"Let him go. He can't do anything."
iwaseteoke
Let them talk
kimi ha keshite yowaku nanka nai
You're far from weak
dare ni mo hatasenakatta yume wo negae tsuyoku
Believe in those dreams no one else could reach!
♪♪～
dare ni mo hatasenakatta yume wo negae tsuyoku
Believe in those dreams no one else could reach!
♪♪～
kanarazu kanaete miserutte
You'll definitely make them come true
saa mizukara no hata kakage
Come, fly your own flag
susume mae ni
and keep moving forward
nijimu namida ha
The tears you shed
kimi no akashi
are proof that you're alive
♪♪～
chikara ni narou
Draw strength from your tears!
mayou toki ha kono boku ga soba ni iru
When you are in trouble, I will be by your side
dakara ikou
So go!
♪♪～
sekai no subete wo mi ni
And see the world
Even if the monarchy is gone, the crimes of the monarchy haven't disappeared!
Reversing the flow of fate?
Wise Solomon, please give this child the
knowledge of miracles to dispel the darkness!
Next time: Kassim's Answer.
15th Night
Kassim's Answer
I will be the one to stop you!
（カシム）王政は消えても
王族の罪は消えない！
運命の逆流？
（ウーゴ）ソロモンよ→
この子に
闇を切り裂く　奇跡の知恵を。
お前は　俺が止める！
昨日、名古屋市西区で
家族３人が殺害された事件で、
警察は、事件後に連絡が取れなく
なっていた
長女と見られる女性が
愛知県小牧市の山林で首をつって
死亡しているのを発見した。